Guide to the New York State 4-H Foundation records, 1948-2016.
New York State 4-H Foundation records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State 4-H Foundation records, 1948-2016.
8663
New York State 4-H Foundation.
6 cubic feet.
Minutes, publications, financial and organizational records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes of the Board of Directors and various other committee meetings, memos, financials, scholarship and trustee files.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Founded in 1949, the New York State Foundation cultivates, secures, and stewards financial resources to support the Cornell Cooperative Extension New York State 4-H program in developing and delivering 4-H youth development programs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes of the Board of Directors and various other committee meetings, memos, financials, scholarship and trustee files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State 4-H Foundation.; Cornell University. Cooperative Extension.
Subjects:
4-H clubs -- New York (State).; Youth -- Societies and clubs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Board of Directors
Series II. Committees
Series III. Reports
Series IV. Programs and Proposals
Series V. Notebooks
Series VI. Policies and Agreements
Series VII. Correspondence and Memos
Series VIII. Publications
CONTAINER LIST
- Board of Directors
  - Meeting minutes, 1948-1986 (Box 1)
    Includes executive committee minutes, proposals, memos, and financials
  - Meeting minutes, 1987-1997 (Box 2)
  - Trustee lists, 1954-2006 (Box 2)
  - Meeting minutes, 1998-2016 (Box 3)
    Includes executive committee minutes, memos, and financials
- Committees
  - Audit committee, 2001-2009 (Box 3)
  - Long range committee, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Trustees development and structure committee, 1983-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Investment committee, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Investment committee, 1990-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Donor acquisition committee, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12A)
  - Finance committee, 1974-1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Finance committee, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Nominating committee, 1975-1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Nominating committee, 1992-2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Finance committee, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Finance committee, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Finance committee, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Fund development committee, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Governance committee, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Listserv committee, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Reports
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 1980-1981-1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 1987-1988-1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 1993-1994-1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 1997-1998-1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Annual 4-H Foundation reports, 2006-2011 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Cumulative reports, 1982-1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Financial reports, 1993-1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Financial reports, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Financial reports, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Executive committee reports, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Visit reports and notes, 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Programs and Proposals
  - Core subject matter programming, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Strategic plan proposal and planning, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Notebooks
  - Trustee notebook, 2000-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1-8)
  - Orientation for 4-H foundation executives resource binder, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Public relations notebook for regional public relations chair, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
- Policies and Agreements
  - Conflict of interest policy, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Liability insurance policy, 2008-2010 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Agreement with Walter Foertsch, 1969-1970 (Box 6)
  - Agreements, 1970-1979 (Box 6)
- Correspondence and Memos
  - Brown Estate at Shackelton's Point, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - New York State 4-H leadership recognition, 1983-1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Liberty Hyde Bailey Founders Society, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Surveys, 1981, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Retreat, 2008-07 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - MOU between Cornell Cooperative Extension and 4-H Foundation, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Scholarship recipients, 2003-2014 (Box 5)
  - Dan Gerow's 4-H scholarship photos, 1999-06-30; CD-5146
  - Donor files, 1988-2014 (Box 6)
  - Trustee files including photographs, 1973-1999 (Box 6)
  - Direct mailings, 1984-1985, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Trustee training, 1980-1996 (Box 6)
  - National trustee workshop, 1984 (Box 6)
  - National trustee workshop, 1997 (Box 6)
  - National trustee workshop, 1998 (Box 6)
  - 4-H centennial postcard and stamps, 2002 (Box 6)
  - 4-H event memos, thank yous, photos, 2009-2012 (Box 6)
- Publications
  - New York State 4-H Foundation publications, 1977-1985 (Box 6)